There really aren't many espers, are there?
（暗田(くらた)トメ）
ホントに
超能力者って少ないのね？
Potato
（暗田）
こんなに通行人がいるのに
１人もピンとこないなんて
All of these people have walked by
and not one has stood out.
あなた まさか
私をダマしてないでしょうね？
You aren't tricking me, are you?
There really haven't been any.
（モブ）
本当に いないだけですよ
（暗田）
ふ～ん
Hey, are you on a date here?
（テル）
やあ！ こんな所でデートかい？
あっ…
えっ 誰？ この特徴的な人
Who is this obviously special guy?
花沢(はなざわ)君
Hanazawa-kun...
悪いね　緊急の用だ
Sorry, this is an emergency.
I'm gonna borrow him for a bit.
彼 ちょっと借りるよ？
ああ…
Him?
Someone's using my name and fighting?
（モブ）
僕を名乗ってケンカ？
Yeah. It's a student from
Salt Middle School.
（テル）
ああ　塩(しお)中の生徒だ
You might know him.
君の知り合いかもな？
He's back there.
You should go see for yourself.
この奥だ
君自身の目で確かめてみてくれ
あっ！
律(りつ)？ 何やってんの？
Ritsu...
What are you doing?
～
Mob Psycho
The Older Brother Bows
~Destructive Intent~
Nii-san... What are you doing here?
（影山(かげやま) 律）
兄さん… なぜ ここに？
律こそ ここで何してるの？
I could ask you the same thing, Ritsu.
（テル）
なんだ 弟か
Oh, that's his younger brother.
Someone just showed up.
（男）
何か 来たな？
Who are all of these people on the ground?
（モブ）
周りに倒れてる人たちは誰？
律がやったの？
Did you do this, Ritsu?
律？
Ritsu?
Yes, I did this.
そう 僕がやった
えっ？
I'm not so boorish as to
watch siblings fight.
（テル）
よそ様の兄弟ゲンカを眺めるほど
ヤボじゃない
Really? You really did this, Ritsu?
（モブ）
本当に… 本当に律が これを？
It's true.
（律）
本当だよ
ウソだ
It's not true.
There's no way you would do this.
律が こんなことするわけないよ！
I mean... seriously...
だって 大体…
ねえ？
Nii-san, I did this.
（律）
兄さん 僕がやったんだ
I obtained psychic powers.
僕は 超能力を手に入れたんだよ
えっ？
Huh?
（エクボ）
待て 律！ 相手は茂夫(しげお)だぞ？
Wait, Ritsu! You're up against Shigeo!
Shut up, Dimple.
（律）
エクボは黙ってろよ！
Tch! He's drunk with power.
（エクボ）
チッ！ 万能感に溺れたか？
This is why I hate brats.
これだから ガキは嫌いなんだ！
I'm not gonna hang around
for a battle I know he'll lose!
負ける戦につきあう気は ねえ！
（律）あっ…
（モブ）エクボ？
Dimple?!
That's fine.
（律）
別にいいさ
もう感覚はつかんだ
I've got the feel of it now.
Nii-san, I've realized
something very important.
兄さん？
僕は大事なことに気が付いたんだ
Ritsu, what's wrong?
律 どうしたの？
何か悩みがあるなら…
If something's bothering you...
（律）
ふん！
（モブ）
あっ…
You really do have psychic powers...
本当に超能力を？
I missed...
（律）
外した
Ritsu...
律…
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
（律）
えっ？
You've wanted to use them for so long!
（モブ）
ずっと使いたがってたもんね！
覚えてる？
Do you remember?
When you were little, you used to cry your
eyes out because you couldn't bend spoons.
律が小さいころに—
スプーン曲げられなくて
泣きじゃくってたの
Who would've thought that now—
まさか 今になって…
（律）
それは つい最近までも同じさ
That hadn't changed up until recently.
Just listen, Nii-san.
いいから聞いてよ？ 兄さん
I've always wanted psychic powers.
僕は超能力に憧れていたんだ
And I've always admired you, Nii-san.
そして 兄さんにも憧れていた
Aw, you're making me blush...
“憧れ”なんて 照れるなあ
But that was a big misunderstanding.
（律）
でも それは
大きな勘違いだったんだ
えっ？
Huh?
I couldn't handle my inferiority complex
and fear towards you,
（律）
僕は兄さんに抱く劣等感と恐怖心に
耐えられなくて
so I was protecting myself by
thinking it was admiration.
憧れだと思い込むことで
自分を守っていたんだ
I was scared of you.
僕は あなたが怖かった
I never knew what you'd do
if you got stressed out.
ストレスがたまると
何をしでかすか分からない
We could never even have
a fight as brothers...
兄弟ゲンカなんて
できたものじゃない
Because I have no way to protect myself
from your powers.
僕には 兄さんの“力”から
自分の身を守るすべがないんだから
So I did my best not to
stress you out in any way.
だから なるべく兄さんが
ストレスをためないように
気を遣ってきた！
Now, that's just a humiliating past.
今じゃ 屈辱の過去だよ
I tried so hard for so long,
ずっと努力はしてたんだ
no matter how crazy it made me...
気が狂いそうな自分を抑えながら
And yet,
なのに
you never worked hard
in your life, so why?
何の努力もしてない兄さんが
なぜ？
But now, I've obtained them.
でも 僕は手に入れた
Now I don't have to be scared anymore.
これで もう恐れることはない
The delusional admiration is gone.
まやかしの憧れも残ってない
というか 今となっては
興味すらうせてしまった
Actually...
Now I've just lost all interest...
“仲良し兄弟”は
ここで終わりだよ 兄さん
The buddy-buddy brothers act
ends now, Nii-san.
Ritsu... I can tell. That's a lie.
律… 分かる
それはウソだね
Face me, right now! Hit me with your powers!
ここで勝負しよう！
僕に“力”をぶつけたっていいよ？
But I guess it's true...
（モブ）
でも 本当なんだね
I'm your brother, Ritsu.
僕は律の兄弟だ
Hey, Ritsu.
ねえ 律？
半分は本当なんだろ？
Half of that is true, right?
（律）
はっ… えっ？
I'm terribly sorry that my
little brother hurt you.
（モブ）
うちの弟がケガをさせてしまって
どうもごめんなさい！
Please still be friends
with him from now on.
今後とも
仲良くしてやってください！
（律）
はあ？
Huh?
What? You're his older brother?
（赤城(あかぎ)）
何だと！
てめえ そいつの兄貴かよ？
Yes. I'm very sorry.
そうです　すみません！
You idiot! You think that's
enough to be forgiven?!
（赤城）
バカ野郎！ そんなんで
許されると思ってんのか？
（五頭(ごず)）
まずは 土下座だろうが！ おら！
You need to grovel first!
O-Okay...
（モブ）
はっ… はい
Hey... Stop.
（律）
おい… やめろ！
Why, Nii-san?
なんでだ？ 兄さん
何やってんだよ！
What are you doing?!
Ritsu... It's no use trying
to get rid of me...
律… 僕を突き放そうとしたって
ムダだよ
Progress Towards
Mob's Explosion
Progress Towards Mob's Explosion: 7%
Because we're brothers.
兄弟なんだから
Hello?
（男）
もしもし
I'd like a status update.
（桜威(さくらい)）
進捗状況を聞きたい
It's been ten minutes since you reported
that you've found the target.
標的発見の連絡から
10分以上たってるぞ？
何をしている？
What are you doing?
I'm just observ—
（男）
ちょっと見学をね
Are you an idiot?
Hurry up and bring him here.
（桜威）
バカか お前は
さっさと連れてこい！
All right.
（男）
分かったよ
Sakurai
Actually, just in case, send a photo.
（桜威）
いや 待て！
念のため 写真を送れ
It'll be troublesome if
you bring the wrong brat.
関係ないガキを
連れてこられても困る
Yeah, yeah...
（男）
はいはい
（男）バカにしやがって！ チッ
How dare he mock me?
There you go. It's sent.
ほらよ 送ったぞ
Confirmed.
（桜威）
確認した
There's no doubt that
that's Kageyama Shigeo.
そいつが影山茂夫で間違いない
Right?
（男）
だろ？
It's just as the data from
the Awakening Lab says.
（桜威）
覚醒ラボのデータにあるとおりだ
チッ 大層な名前 付けやがって！
What an exaggerated name.
It's embarrassing to say.
口に出すのが
恥ずかしいじゃないか！
Listen up.
いいか？ ヘマするなよ！
Don't mess this up.
The more information we leak,
the more annoying it'll be.
情報を与えるほど
面倒になるからな
遊ぶなよ？
Don't play around.
Yeah, yeah...
偉そうにしやがって…
Acting all high-and-mighty...
Now, then...
さてと！
（ヤンキーたち）
アハハハハ
The tables have turned!
（五頭）
形勢逆転～！
White T Poison!
（赤城）
白Ｔ(しろティー)ポイズン！
If you don't want us to beat the crap out
of your brother, get your face over here.
兄貴をボコられたくなかったら
お前が顔面を差し出しな～！
（モブ）
あ… 待った！
そんなことしちゃダメだよ
Hold it.
You shouldn't do that.
Huh?
（ヤンキー）
ああ？
I don't want to see anyone
else hurting people,
もう 傷つけるのも
傷つけられるのも
僕は見たくない！
or anyone else getting hurt.
Who the hell do you think
you are, small fry?!
雑魚が図に乗るんじゃねえぞ！
こら～！
Only the strongest can give orders.
（磐梯(ばんだい)）
命令できんのは 強いヤツだけだ
And the strongest will rule.
（富士(ふじ)）
いちばん強いヤツが
その場を制する
Just how pathetic are these people?
（律）
どこまでも滑稽(こっけい)な人たちだ
The strongest one here is...
この場で
いちばん強さを持つのは…
（律）うっ うわ…
You're exactly right.
（男）
そのとおりだ！
（律）
うっ… 誰だ？
Who are you?
律！
Ritsu!
What?
Who's that?
何だって？
Who the hell are you?!
The strongest will rule.
（男）
いちばん強いヤツが場を制する！
当たり前すぎて 忘れがちな摂理だ
It's such an obvious thing
that you forget about it.
You guys figure that
if you're strong at fighting,
お前たちの物差しでは
ケンカが強ければ 学校 地区を
制することができるのだろう？
you can rule your school
and turfs, right?
That's cute. You should keep it up.
かわいい指標だな
せいぜい頑張るといい
But he's on a different level.
だが こいつは別格だ！
You guys don't have a chance of beating him.
お前たちでは
万が一にも 勝つことは不可能！
あぐ…
So I'm going to remove him
from the fighting grounds.
（男）
だから 同じ土俵から下ろしてやる
You can continue your squabbling in peace.
安心して“小競り合い”に励め！
I'll be taking him.
こいつは俺が預かる
Hold it!
待て こら～！
そいつは俺たちの獲物…
He's our target!
うわ～！
You're just an outsider!
（ヤンキー）
部外者のくせに…
うわっ！ おわ～！
How dare you do that to our boss?!
よくも番長を…
Hey, don't.
おい！ やめとけって！
（２人）
うわ～！
T-Too strong...
（ヤンキーたち）
つ… 強すぎる
反則だろ？
That's not fair...
（男）
ハハハハハ
まったく 分かりやすい動物たちだ
You thugs are such simple creatures...
不良っつうのは
あ？
My little brother...
弟を…
N-Nii-san...
にっ 兄さん
Did I hit him too hard?
（男）
強く当て過ぎたか？
Well, if he dies,
I'd say he was just unlucky.
（ざわめき）
まあ 死んでたら 運が悪かったな
Hey, you good-for-nothing.
（男）そこのウド野郎！
（富士）うっ…
What's with that rebellious stare?
（男）
何だよ？ その反抗的な目は
いや 別に…
見てただけじゃないですか？
It's not! I was just looking...
Grovel, and apologize to me.
（男）
土下座して 俺に謝れ！
Huh?
ええ？
We're reviewing the scene
you were playing out earlier.
（男）
さっきまでのドラマの おさらいだ
I know! All of you should grovel.
そうだ！
お前ら全員 土下座しろよ！
Will this make you a little more willing?
こう言えば 必死になれるか？
If you don't grovel, I'll kill all of you.
“土下座しないと 全員 殺す！”
フッフフフ
ハハハハ！ 壮観だな～！
What a great sight!
It's a great lesson for idiots
who mistake youth and freedom.
若さと自由を
履き違えるバカどもには
いい教訓になっただろう
I've got one piece of advice for
the rest of your rotten lives.
今後の廃れた人生に
１つアドバイスをしてやろう
Try to live your lives walking on the
side of the road as much as possible,
なるべく
人様に迷惑をかけないよう
so you don't cause anyone else trouble.
歩道の隅っこを歩くように生きろよ
See ya, brats.
じゃあな！ クソガキども
ウハハハハ ア～ハッハッハ！
Damn it!
（ヤンキーたち）
クソッ！
何だったんだ？
What was that?
（富士）
ん？
That's...
あいつは…
（モブ）
くっ…
律～！
Ritsu!
（ヤンキーたち）
うわあ～！
（男）
ん？
（誇山(こやま)）
ぐあっ！
You, too, brat?
（誇山）
小僧 お前もか？
にっ 兄さん…
N-Nii-san...
超能力持ちの兄弟がいるなんて
聞いてねえぞ！
I wasn't told about a psychic brother.
Let go of my brother...
（モブ）
弟を放せ！ じゃないと…
or else...
（律）
あっ！
Oh, so you've put up a barrier?
（誇山）
おっ？ 一丁前に
バリアなんて張ってやがんのか？
I'm not supposed to use
these powers against others,
（モブ）
人に向けちゃ ダメだ！
but this is different!
けど 今は別だ！
ナメるなよ？ クソガキ！
Don't underestimate me, brat.
はっ！
I remember now!
（モブ）
思い出した！
He's the adult esper I saw before...
この人 いつか見た
大人の超能力者だ
There are ways to deal with
little esper brats like you.
超能力者のガキには—
それ用の
お仕置きのしかたってもんがある！
えいやっ！
おおおお～！ 念動螺旋(らせん)！
Telekinetic Helix!
Telekinetic Helix
（モブ）
また殴ってくる
He's attacking again. I don't want
to become an adult like him.
こういう大人になりたくないな
Cry.
泣けよ！
（モブ）
えっ？
Huh?
くっくく…
You're so light. You fly up really well.
軽いな～ よく飛ぶ～
It hurts...
（モブ）
苦しい… 息が吐けない 吸えない
I can't exhale...
or inhale...
My stomach is hot...
おなかが熱い！
ああ… うっ うえ…
（誇山）
驚いたか？
You surprised?
My powers rip through your
barrier like an excavator.
俺の技は お前のバリアを
掘削機のように うがつ
Nii-san!
兄さん！
Stand up.
（誇山）
立てよ！
You're going to protect your
little brother, right?
弟を守るんだろ？
Oh, crap.
（磐梯）ああ マズい！
（赤城）殴られ過ぎているぞ？
He's hitting him way too much.
You can't be serious...
（ヤンキーたち）
ウソだろ？ 死ぬぞ！
マジかよ
He's gonna die.
Seriously?
Nii-san?
兄さん
S-Stop...
や… やめろ！
もう やめてくれ～！
Please, stop!
（誇山）う～りゃ！
（モブ）ぐはっ…
Stop!
（律）
もう やめろ～！
Just take me! That's what
you wanted, right?
僕を連れていけ！
それが目的なんだろ？ だから…
That's a wise decision,
（誇山）
賢明な判断だが
フフフフ 俺は意地悪でね
but I'm an asshole.
I don't like that look on your face...
その顔が気に入らんな～
That hostile little face!
敵意満々の その顔がなあ！
（モブ）
おい お前…
Hey, you.
This is the first time this has happened.
こんなの 初めてだ！
Can you feel it?
分かるか？ なあ
My animosity?
僕の敵意！
Mob Psycho
（誇山）
うわっ！
この俺が 手をつかされた？
あんなガキに…
He made me put my hands to the ground...
A brat like that...
（誇山）
うわっ！
ううっ うう… うっうっう
I can't get away!
放さねえと… ええっ？
がはっ！
あの男 終わった
That guy is finished.
Hey, mister, who did terrible things to us...
（モブ）
僕たちに ひどいことをした
大人のおにいさん？
言っとくけど
お前のせいだからな！
Just so you know, this is all your fault.
Don't ever show your face
in front of us again.
二度と僕たちの前に顔を出すな！
Telekinetic Helix!
（誇山）
念動螺旋！
It's hard?! It's nothing like before...
堅い！ さっきとは別物！
（ヤンキーたち）
おお… すっげ～
見たか？ おい！
Wow...
Hey, did you see that?
What was that?
（ヤンキー）
何だよ？ 今の
What's going on?
どうなってんだ？
ああっ！ ウソだろ？
You're kidding!
Energy Bomb!
（誇山）
エネルギー・ボム！
この俺に
奥の手まで使わせやがって！
You're actually making me
use my trump card...
Nii-san!
（律）
兄さん？
Why won't he fall over?
チェッ…
（誇山）
なんで倒れねえ？
At this rate, things won't end well...
（エクボ）
このままじゃ ヤベえ！
I know! If I bring him here...
そうだ！ あいつを連れてくれば…
おりゃ～！
Damn it! What's with this brat?
（誇山）
クソ！ 何だよ このガキ？
うわあ！
H-He's strong!
（誇山）
つ… 強(つえ)え！
If I don't put up my guard,
I'll be knocked out in an instant.
気を張らないと
一瞬で意識が飛ばされちまう
（ヤンキーたち）
うお～ すげえ！
いいぞ やっちまえ！
Whoa!
Yeah! Get him!
（磐梯）
あんなヤツが いたなんて…
To think a guy like that existed...
（富士）
おい！ あれ
Hey, look!
見ろ！ “白いＴシャツ”だ！
It's a white T-shirt!
（磐梯）
あっ そうか！
That's it!
He's not White T Poison's older brother...
白Ｔポイズンの兄じゃ
なかったんだ！
He's the infamous shadow leader
at Salt Middle School...
ヤツが ウワサの塩中学校 裏番…
White T Poison!
（ヤンキーたち）
白Ｔポイズン！
Taking him on in a battle
of abilities isn't good.
（誇山）
能力での勝負は 分が悪(わり)い
I don't have a choice.
The mission comes first.
しかたねえ！
任務が最優先だしな
He's got a knife! Look out!
刃物だ！ 気をつけろ！
Shut up, brat!
（誇山）
うるせえ！ ガキが！
おりゃ～！
If you're not going to give up, I'll end it.
（モブ）
しつこいなら 終わらせてやる！
次で とどめだ！
The next move will be the last.
Take this, brat!
食らえ 小僧！
Damn it!
クソッ！ なんて分厚いバリアだ！
This barrier's so thick!
My knife won't go through!
これじゃあ ナイフが通らねえ！
Just kidding!
（誇山）
なんてな！
（モブ）ああ…
（ヤンキー）ああ 何だ？
What?
I don't like using his stuff,
but I don't have time.
（誇山）
あいつの道具に頼るのは
不本意だが
ゆっくりも してられねえ！
顔を見られたんだったな？
I guess you've all seen my face.
As annoying as it is, I'm gonna
have to make you all disappear.
面倒だが 全員 消すしかないか
C-Crap!
（ヤンキーたち）
ヤバい 逃げるぞ！
はっ 走ろう！
Run!
H-Hurry!
（誇山）
ヘヘヘ… さんざん見物しておいて
逃がすと思うか？
Do you really think I'll let you
get away after everything you saw?
ん？
（誇山）
バカな？
これ以上 相手はできん！
Impossible! I can't take him on anymore!
You're coming with me.
お前は来い！
Did we survive?
俺たち 助かったのか？
（ヤンキーたち）
よっしゃ～！
助かった～！
Yeah!
We did it!
We're saved!
Awesome!
（磐梯）
すげえよ あんた！
You're amazing!
俺たちの恩人だぜ！
You saved our lives!
あれ？
Huh?
He's standing while unconscious.
気絶したまま立ってる
Get away from him.
It's still dangerous to be near him.
（テル）
彼から離れろ！
まだ 近づくのは危険だぞ
You're from Black Vinegar Middle School...
（ヤンキー）
お前は黒酢(くろず)中の…
I can't believe someone was
able to push him this far.
彼をここまで追い詰めるなんて
信じられない
They're no ordinary person.
ただ者じゃないな？
The guy and Ritsu are gone.
We were a bit late.
（エクボ）
男も律の姿もない！
ひと足 遅かったか～
Spirits and Such
Consultation Office
This is rock salt from the Himalayas.
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
これは ヒマラヤ産の岩塩です
It goes great with pasta or meat.
パスタや肉にも
よく合うんですけど
Let's perform the exorcism with this.
今回は こいつを使って
除霊しましょう
Your shoulders feel heavy, right?
肩が重いんですよね？
（女性）
はい…
Yes. A fortuneteller told me
there was something on them.
占い師には“何かが乗ってる”って
言われて…
So they just told her that and took
the money? How irresponsible.
（霊幻）
言うだけ言って 金取るのかよ？
無責任な業者だな
分かりました！
All right.
Wh-What are you doing?
あっ… 何を？
幽霊は 塩分に弱いですからね
まず 岩塩の粉末で弱らせます
Ghosts are weak against salt.
First, we'll weaken it with
the rock salt powder.
And this scraping noise by your ears...
あと この耳元での騒音
This will be really annoying to spirits
that want to live in a quiet place,
静かな場所を好んで生息する
霊にとっては
so they should leave.
迷惑で離れたくなるはず！
次に！
Next!
We'll use the hard edges of
the rock salt and do a massage
岩塩のゴツゴツを
利用したマッサージで
to loosen up your tense muscles
and improve your blood flow.
こわばった筋肉をほぐし
血流を良くします
（女性）
ああ… ああ～
We'll place a hot towel on your face,
（霊幻）
蒸気で温めたタオルを顔にかぶせて
霊の視覚干渉をシャットアウト
and shut out the spirit's
visual interference.
Along with using aroma oils
to maximize your relaxation,
アロマオイルでリラックス効果を
高めるとともに
we'll light some incense that spirits hate.
霊が苦手な お香をたきます
（女性）
なっ 何て いい匂い～！
S-Such a wonderful smell!
Aroma Runaway Express!
アロマ暴走特急！
Aroma
Runaway Express
（ナレーション）
心と体をリラックスさせ
This is one of Reigen's special moves,
where he sends his clients on a beauty trip
美容効果てきめんの
旅へと いざなう—
霊幻の必殺技である
that relaxes the body and soul.
何だか若返った気がします
I feel so much younger.
That's great!
それは よかった！
Thank goodness there was
no actual spirit this time,
（霊幻）
今回は ガチなやつじゃなくて
助かったが
but this is the first time Mob
didn't show up to work on time.
モブが 約束の時間を
無断で破るなんて初めてだ
I'm gonna have to lecture him
when I see him next.
次 会ったときは説教だな！
（律）
兄さん
Nii-san.
If there's anything troubling you,
let me know.
何か悩みがあるなら言ってよ
いつでも相談に乗るから
I'll be there to listen anytime.
兄さん 悩んでない？
Nii-san, is something bothering you?
大丈夫？ 兄さん
Are you okay, Nii-san?
If something's bothering you, I'll listen.
何か悩んでたら 相談 乗るよ？
Thanks, Ritsu, but I'm fine.
ありがとう 律
でも 大丈夫　何でもないよ
It's nothing.
そう…
I see.
Ritsu?
（モブ）
律… 律？
Ritsu?
I see...
そうか 気付いてあげられなくて
ごめんね
I'm sorry I didn't realize it sooner.
ううっ ああ…
目が覚めたか？ 影山君
Are you awake, Kageyama-kun?
Hanazawa-kun... where are we?
（モブ）
花沢君！ ここは？
My apartment. Dimple-kun told me everything.
（テル）
僕のアパートだ
話はエクボ君から聞いたよ
H-Hey, Shigeo...
よっ よう！ 茂夫
Dimple...
（モブ）
エクボ どういうことだ？
What's going on?
Why were you with Ritsu?
なんで律と一緒に？
そりゃあ…
Well...
And Ritsu was kidnapped.
（モブ）
それに 律がさらわれた！
Dimple...
エクボ… お前のせいなのか？
Is this your doing?
誤解だ！ 俺 あんなヤツ知らねえ！
It's a misunderstanding!
I don't know who those guys are!
僕は知っている
I know who they are.
（モブとエクボ）
えっ？
Huh?
They've been following me around
for a few years now.
数年前から
連中に つけ狙われている
（モブとエクボ）
えっ！
Is that why you're living by yourself
when you're in middle school?
（エクボ）
だから
中学生で独り暮らしなのか？
１つ 忠告してあげよう
Let me give you a warning.
Stay away from them.
（テル）ヤツらとは関わるな！
（エクボ）ん？
Stay away?
“関わるな”って…
死ぬよ！
You'll die.
くっ…
It's an organization called Claw,
formed by dangerous espers.
（テル）
ヤバい超能力者が
結託した組織“爪”
They want a revolution
and aim to turn the world on its head.
革命を起こし
世界転覆をもくろんでいる
Their ability to function
as a group is first-rate,
その組織力は群を抜いていて
100人以上の超能力者を有している
and they have over a hundred espers.
え～っ ウソだろ？
You're kidding, right?
A hundred...
100人？
There are plenty of facilities
across the world that are trying to
（テル）
人工的な超能力の開発を
目指す施設は
manufacture psychic powers.
世界各地に たくさんある
But the only one to succeed at it is Claw.
でも その実験を成功させたのは
世界でも“爪”だけだ
Apparently they take child espers
who have yet to mature,
まだ成熟してない
子供の超能力者を洗脳して
brainwash them, and raise them as soldiers.
兵隊に育て上げるらしい
They aren't as powerful as us Naturals,
僕ら“ナチュラル”より
“力”は劣るが
but if you underestimate them,
their sheer numbers will easily crush you.
ナメてかかると
数で簡単に潰されるよ？
（エクボ）
お前 詳しいな？
You sure know a lot about them.
I heard all about them from one of their
guys who tried to kidnap me before.
以前 僕を
さらおうとした組織の人に
聞いたからね
そいつは念入りに
こらしめといてやったけど
Though I taught him a lesson.
何にしても ヤツは
ヤバい世界の人間だったな～
Basically, they're from
a very dangerous world.
茂夫 お前
下手したら殺されてたぞ？
Shigeo, you could've been killed back there!
It doesn't matter...
（モブ）
知らないよ
Ritsu, my little brother, was kidnapped.
律が… 弟が さらわれたんだ！
I'm going to go save him.
助けに行く！
（テル）
死にたいのか？
Do you want to die?
No, not at all.
いや 全然！
だったら 落ち着けよ！
Then calm down.
But I think I can win.
（モブ）
勝てると思うから！
（テル）
うっ…
ハア…
分かったよ
All right.
But why are they after your little brother?
でも どうして
君の弟なんだろうな？
さっぱり分からない
I have no idea.
Ah! That's right!
あっ そういえば！
There's a research facility where
people like you were gathering.
お前らと同類が集まる研究所が
あるんだ！
Ritsu was going there recently, too.
律も最近 そこに通ってた！
律が？
Ritsu was?
So the information must
have leaked from there.
そこから情報が漏れたな
Want to check it out?
確かめてみるか？
嫌な予感しかしないが…
Though, I have a terrible feeling about this...
案内するぜ！
I'll lead you there.
（エクボ）
うわ！ こりゃ ひでえなあ
一般人相手に
This is terrible...
How could they do this to civilians?
They're unconscious, but not dead.
（テル）
意識を飛ばされているが
死んではいない
（密裏賢治(みつうらけんじ)）
ゴホッ ゴホッ
Wh-Who are you?! Where did he go?
きっ 君たちは？
ヤツは どこに行った？ 刀の男は？
The guy with the sword!
こっちの質問が先だ！
You'll need to answer our questions first.
Did you sell Kageyama Ritsu's
information to Claw?
あんた 影山 律の情報を
“爪”に売ったのか？
Claw? What's that?
爪？ 何だ？ そりゃ
Kageyama Ritsu?
影山 律？
I don't know who that is.
知らないぞ！
私が声をかけたのは
影山茂夫君だ！
The one I invited here
was Kageyama Shigeo-kun.
That's me.
それは僕だ！
君が？
That's you?!
人違いから始まったのに
ホントに律を覚醒(せい)させちまったな
This all started with a misunderstanding,
and yet they really managed
to awaken Ritsu.
I have no idea what's going on.
（密裏）
何が どうなってるんだ？
Damn it...
クソ～！ せっかく研究に
光明が見えてきたのに…
And we were finally seeing some
hope in our research, too.
Looks like this guy doesn't know anything.
（テル）
このおっさんは
何も知らないっぽいね
Where are the other kids?
（モブ）
ほかの子たちは？
They were kidnapped...
さらわれた
私のせいなのか？
Is this my fault?
To think there are people like them...
あんなヤツが いるなんて！
What kind of level of power did
the kids who were kidnapped have?
さらわれた子たちの“力”は
どの程度だったんだ？
I'd like to know to know
what we're up against.
現状の戦力分析の参考にしたい
ちょっと待ってくれ！
君たちは何なの… ああ！
Hold on a sec. Who are you guys?
何してんの？ 花沢君
What are you doing, Hanazawa-kun?
自己紹介
Introducing ourselves.
Come on, brats. Hurry up and get out.
（誇山）
ほら～ クソガキども
さっさと降りろ！
Quit dawdling. Keep moving.
モタモタすんな！
とっとと進め！
Don't make me spank you.
ケツ ひっぱたくぞ！
Don't scare them more than necessary.
They'll be useless then.
必要以上に
怖がらせるな
使えなくなる
（誇山）
チッ
Kageyama, are you okay?
（星野武史(ほしの　たけし)）
影山 そのケガ
平気なのか？
僕は 大丈夫
I'm fine, but we really shouldn't
fight back right now.
でも 今は
抵抗しないほうがいい
あっ…
～
Trapped in a suspicious research facility,
（霊幻）
怪しい研究所に監禁された律は
Ritsu tries to plot an escape
with the good-for-nothing espers.
ポンコツ超能力者たちと
脱出を企てる
Meanwhile, Mob rises to save Ritsu.
一方 律を救うため 立ち上がるモブ
That's right, Mob!
That's what you call a man.
そうだ モブ！
それでこそ 男ってもんだぜ！
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Episode 9:
次回「モブサイコ100」
第９話“‘爪’　第７支部”
"'Claw' ~7th Division~"
"Claw"
~7th Division~
Option B, the serious course, involves buying
the Blu-rays and the manga volumes.
真面目Ｂコースなら
ブルーレイと単行本！